Why, for example, Zenon meant that reality must be an illusion.
To explain this, Aristotle also introduced the concept of "potential".
Built into all matter, there was the potential to become some things.
In an acorns there is the potential to become an oak, however, not to become a dog.
When something has adopted its form, the potential has been updated.
The thing has now become what it can be.
In addition, there is an intention, one purpose, built into everything.
The reason why the acorn strives to become an oak is to secure the species' survival.
Just like his predecessor Plato was Aristotle interested in how to create
Democracy was a matter only for free men, he said.
He assumed that man was a social being,
A political animal that wanted to live with other people.
For this to work, a strict hierarchy was required;
At the bottom of the slave then the children, the wife and at the top man.
This was the natural order and the system would lead to good and safe life.
When the individual has accepted her role, she also becomes happy.
The state's task was to help each family, and, by extension, every individual, to reach this good life.
In the book "The Nikomachian ethics" Aristotle describes its view of ethics and morality.
We are not controlled by instincts but by reason and free will.
We also have no congenital knowledge of right and wrong, good or bad,
Without this, we must learn through training.
We become friendly by performing friendly actions, moderate by performing moderate actions, etc.
By developing and refining their virtues, its positive qualities, we will become better people.
Thus we will automatically act right in different situations
Then good documents originate from good traits.
There are two types of virtues - moral and intellectual.
A good person is also a happy person, Aristotle says.
We all strive to live as social creatures in a society, something that a virtuous person is easy for.
To become virtuous, we must have a balanced attitude to our emotions and desires.
Where this golden middle ground goes varies from person to person, but he gives some simple examples:
Courage is the balance between dumbness and cowardice, generosity is the balance between waste and greed.
The goal of happiness thus goes by learning to become a balanced personality - to be adequate.
As a philosopher, Aristotle was in many ways different from his predecessors.
His research was systematic and based on careful observations of the world
And his philosophy is mostly about what we would call science today.
Thus, there is a clear link between Aristotle and the natural philosophers.
Throughout his life, he immersed himself in research in a way that is unparalleled in Western history,
And his influence is difficult to overestimate.
His geocentric worldview, but the earth in the middle and the planets revolve around this,
was prevailing until the 16th century when Nicolaus Copernicus, Galileo Galilei and Tycho Brahe
Could prove the heliocentric worldview - that it is the sun that is at the center.
This was largely due to the fact that the Catholic Church used his thoughts to construct his worldview.
The Bible's view of creation is also compatible with Aristotle's view
that everything has a built -in purpose, an intention.
To be able to conduct his science, he needed deeper insight into how correct conclusions worked.
The rules for this were not yet known, after which Aristotle created what is today known as logic.
It was not until the end of the 19th century that this logic came to be further developed into what it is today.
Aristotle's engaging with virtually all the sciences of the time, except for mathematics,
And was probably the most learned man of antiquity.
He was the one who mapped many of the sciences we have today - and studies rhetoric or dramaturgy
Is it still Aristotle's virtually unchanged works that you read.
His categorization of plants and animals were prevailing
Until Carl von Linné launched his systematization during the 18th century.
To manage his research, he categorized philosophy in four different categories:
Physics, metaphysics, logic and ethics.
This is a division that we, with some modification, still have today.